CIO Files of John L. Lewis, Pt. II: CIO General Files on Microfilm 5831 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Minutes, Correspondence, and General Files, 1939-1941 (Reel 4)
  - Los Angeles Industrial Union Council--Harry Bridges, president (CIO financial assistance for West Coast organizing drive)., 1939; 3 (Reel 4)
    7 pp.: CIO financial assistance for West Coast organizing drive@United Studio Technicians Guild; Harry Bridges; J. Raymond Bell; John Brophy.
  - CIO--Executive Board Meeting., 1939; 4 (Reel 4)
    June 1939. 4 pp.: News release.
  - CIO--Executive Board Meeting., 1939; 5 (Reel 4)
    October 5, 1939. 14 pp.: List of motions passed at meeting; minutes of meeting; J. Raymond Bell; Kathryn Lewis; Mervyn Rathborne; Allan S. Haywood; John L. Coulter; James B. Carey; Lee Pressman.
  - CIO Convention., 1939; 6 (Reel 4)
    70 pp.: Constitution; UMWA report; UMWA delegates; credentials; resolutions on the war in Europe; committee memberships; report of committee on legislation; report of the president; greetings to convention; Martin Wagner; John O'Leary; John Brophy; Robert F. Wagner.
  - CIO--Releases. 1939 (part 1)., 7 (Reel 4)
    221 pp.: AFL proposal for amendment of the Wagner Act; wage and hour legislation; Fair Labor Standards Act; legislative programs; Social Security committee; national health bill; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; violations of free speech and rights of labor by strikebreaking services; Homer Martin UAW controversy; Labor's Non-Partisan League; federal relief spending cuts; John Brophy; Lee Pressman; Walter Smethurst; Harvey C. Fremming; Joseph Kovner; Robert M. La Follette; Sidney Hillman; Philip Murray; Franklin D. Roosevelt; Ralph Hetzel; Anthony Wayne Smith.
  - CIO--Releases. 1939 (Part 2)., 8 (Reel 4)
    205 pp.: Founding of United Construction Workers Organizing Committee; legislative programs; local industrial union organization; AFL-CIO competition; press allegations of Communist influence in CIO; health and welfare programs; Labor Day speeches; AFL factionalism and internal politics; proposed amendment of Wagner Act; WPA legislation; Lee Pressman; John Brophy; Joseph Kovner; Ralph Hetzel.
  - CIO--Audits and Accounting., 1939; 9 (Reel 4)
    38 pp.: Financial matters; UMWA loans to CIO; J. Raymond Bell.
  - CIO--Housing Committee., 1939; 10 (Reel 4)
    21 pp.: US Housing Authority low-rent housing programs; Havana Labor Congress; report on the International Congress for Housing and Town Planning; plans for 1939 CIO convention; Federation of Architects, Engineers, Chemists, and Technicians; Anthony Wayne Smith; John Anderson; John Brophy; Michael Quill; John M. Ross.
  - CIO--Legislative Committee and Legal Department., 1939-1941; 11 (Reel 4)
    1939 [and 1941]. 67 pp.: Legislative programs; industrial mobilization plans of the AFL and the National Association of Manufacturers; CIO negotiations with UOPWA CIO office unit; US Supreme Court decision regarding Jersey City, NJ, civil rights case; NLRB decision; AFL proposed amendment of the Wagner Act@United Kingdom financial matters (1941); Lee Pressman; Anthony Wayne Smith; Joseph Kovner; Kathryn Lewis.
  - CIO--Organization Director., 1939; 12 (Reel 4)
    10 pp.: 1939 CIO convention; call for a southern conference on organization; CIO organizers; Aluminum Workers of America; CIO regional directors; Allan S. Haywood; August Scholle; Michael J. Kosik; Walter Harris.
  - CIO--Social Security Committee., 1939; 13 (Reel 4)
    25 pp.: Social Security legislation; Joseph Kovner.
  - CIO--Unemployment Committee., 1939; 14 (Reel 4)
    20 pp.: WPA legislation; relief programs in Kentucky, Alabama, and West Virginia in connection with UMWA contract negotiations; Ralph Hetzel; James E. Murray; A.D. Lewis.
  - CIO--Committee on Latin American Affairs., 1939-1941; 15 (Reel 4)
    178 pp. [continued on Reel 5]: Appeal from Dominican Republic labor leaders; Mexico City meetings of the Confederation of Latin American Workers (CTAL); report of the Pan-American Maritime Council; ILO; Philip Murray; Nelson A. Rockefeller; Kathryn Lewis; J. Raymond Bell; Edward Gordon; Ad Staal; Joseph Curran; Thomas Kennedy; Reid Robinson; Ralph Hetzel; Harold Ruttenberg; Anthony Wayne Smith; Ernest Galarza; James B. Carey; Jacob Baker; James Robinson.
- Minutes, Correspondence, and General Files, 1939-1941 (Reel 5)
  - CIO--Committee on Latin American Affairs., 1939-1941; 1 (Reel 5)
    246 pp. [continued from Reel 4]: Pan-American Union; entertainment of Latin American visitors; Cuban Labor Congress; Havana Conference of the ILO; US legislation for international cooperation; minutes of meetings; Mexico City meeting of the Latin American Congress of Trade Unions; fascism; Kathryn Lewis; Anthony Wayne Smith; Reid Robinson; Joseph Kovner; John Brophy; Ray Torr; James B. Carey; Isador Lubin; David Fowler; Ernest Galarza; Sherman H. Dalrymple; Lee Pressman; Michael Quill; Joseph Curran; Mervyn Rathborne.
  - CIO--General., 1940; 2 (Reel 5)
    191 pp.: Support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; legislative programs; 1940 US presidential campaigns of Franklin D. Roosevelt and Wendell Willkie; support for CIO presidency of John L. Lewis; economic impact of national defense mobilization; union shop; SWOC; Consumers Power Corporation; protests against federal budget cuts; economic analysis of industrial trends; payment on United Packinghouse Workers of America loan from CIO; CIO personnel matters; CIO organizers and regional directors; UMWA organizers; leave of absence granted to John Brophy; lists of officers of national and international affiliates and CIO regional and subregional directors; J. Raymond Bell; Thomas Kennedy; Kathryn Lewis; Walter Smethurst; Allan S. Haywood; Lee Pressman; Rinaldo Cappellini; Ralph Hetzel; Len De Caux; Ora E. Gasaway; Henry Allai; Charles Funcannon; James Robb; John Brophy; Van A. Bittner.
  - CIO--Executive Board Meetings. February-November, 1940; 3 (Reel 5)
    47 pp.: Legislative programs; union organization; housing committee report; Social Security committee report; unemployment division report; national defense mobilization; WPA; Michael Quill; Anthony Wayne Smith; Sherman H. Dalrymple; Emil Rieve; Ralph Hetzel; Franklin D. Roosevelt.
  - CIO--Convention., 1940; 4 (Reel 5)
    73 pp.: UMWA delegation; committee memberships; speeches; national defense mobilization; constitution; Ralph Hetzel; Kathryn Lewis; Philip Murray; Sidney Hillman; James B. Carey.
- Minutes, Correspondence, and General Files, 1940-1941 (Reel 6)
  - CIO--Publicity and Pamphlets., 1940; 1 (Reel 6)
    102 pp.: Proposed amendment of Wagner Act; union organization; youth employment; national defense mobilization; growth in CIO membership; American Youth Congress; social security programs; organization of black workers; National Negro Congress; legislative programs; anti-war activities; Len De Caux; Joseph H. Padway; Gilbert Montague; Sherman H. Dalrymple; Joseph Kovner; Van A Bittner.
  - CIO--Audits and Accounting., 1940; 2 (Reel 6)
    72 pp.: Financial matters; national and international union payments of per capita and assignments of CIO organizers; Leo F. T. Tearney.
  - CIO--Housing Committee., 1940; 3 (Reel 6)
    4 pp.: U.S. Housing Authority appropriations; legislative programs; Michael Quill; Anthony Wayne Smith.
  - CIO--Legislative Committee and Legal Department., 1940; 4 (Reel 6)
    76 pp.: Legislative programs; proposed amendments to CIO constitution; national defense contracting policies; legislative committee report to executive board; foreign exchange assets and needs of countries fighting against Germany; Lee Pressman; Anthony Wayne Smith; Joseph Kovner.
  - CIO--Marine Maritime Committee., 1940; 5 (Reel 6)
    42 pp.: Earl King, Ernest G. Ramsey, and Frank J. Connor murder case in California; political activities; opposition to nominations of John J. Dempsey and Joseph K. Carson to US Maritime Commission; anti-union policies of US Maritime Commission; Pan-American Maritime Federation; Harry Bridges deportation case; Bjorne Halling; Joseph Curran; James B. Carey.
  - CIO--Organization Director., 1940; 6 (Reel 6)
    38 pp.: Support for 1940 US presidential campaign of Wendell Willkie; Utility Workers Organizing Committee; Consumers Power Corporation NLRB elections; UAW; CIO organization plans; CIO organizers and regional directors; financial difficulties with UOPWA and CIO loans; AFL organization of industrial insurance agents; UERMWA contract negotiations; 1940 UMWA convention; AFL-CIO competition; Allan S. Haywood; Kathryn Lewis; William Collins; James B. Carey.
  - CIO--Replies to Release regarding National Labor Relations Act and Government Contracts., 1940; 7 (Reel 6)
    194 pp.: Proposed guarantees of collective bargaining in government contracts that would debar firms violating NLRA from receiving such contracts; local and national union support for proposals; Advisory Commission to the Council of National Defense; proposed executive order; proposed amendments to Walsh-Healey Act; Van A. Bittner; Sidney Hillman; Samuel J. Hogan; Frank Hefferly; Morris Muster; Franklin D. Roosevelt; Harold J. Pritchett; Edward T. Cheyfitz; Michael J. Quill; Lewis Merrill; Sam Nicholls; Richard Francis; Marcel Scherer; John Green; Thomas Kennedy; Philip Murray; O.F. Nigro; James B. Carey; Julius Emspak; Frank McCarty; Ralph Hetzel; Abram Flaxer; Jacob Baker; Reid Robinson; Morris Watson; N.A. Zonarich; Donald Henderson; Joseph Curran; John Brophy; Lee Pressman.
  - CIO--Unemployment Committee., 1940; 8 (Reel 6)
    60 pp.: US government unemployment statistics; US Civil Service employment opportunities; WPA budget appropriations; legislative programs; economic analysis of industrial production; unemployment committee report; Ralph Hetzel.
  - CIO--Women's Auxiliary., 1940; 9 (Reel 6)
    24 pp.: National Coordinating Committee for Women's Auxiliaries; anti-war policies; educational programs; WPA programs. Julia Katz; Kathryn Lewis; Mary Santo.
  - CIO--General., 1941; 10 (Reel 6)
    240 pp.: Requests for union organization of office, domestic, and restaurant workers; requests for miscellaneous information; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; NLRB elections; labor problems in national defense contracts; IWA factionalism and internal politics; Robert F. Wagner; John T. Jones; Philip Murray; Kathryn Lewis; Harry Bridges.
  - CIO--Office General., 1941; 11 (Reel 6)
    100 pp.: Support for UMWA contract negotiations in the captive mines dispute; National Defense Mediation Board; Office of Production Management; wartime mobilization plans; expansion of UMWA District 50; CIO factionalism and internal politics; legislative programs; national defense mobilization; lists of CIO regional and sub-regional directors, officers of national and international affiliates, and district, county, and city industrial union councils; Allan S. Haywood; Walter Smethurst; James B. Carey; Sidney Hillman; Philip Murray; Michael F. Widman; Lee Pressman; Ralph Hetzel; John Brophy; Earl E. Houck; K.C. Adams; Ora E. Gasaway; Percy Tetlow; Thomas Kennedy; Franklin D. Roosevelt; J. Raymond Bell.
  - CIO--Executive Board Meetings., 1941; 12 (Reel 6)
    4 pp.: Resolution in support of United Construction Workers Organizing Committee; plans for meeting; James B. Carey.
- Minutes, Correspondence, and General Files, 1941-1942 (Reel 7)
  - CIO--Convention. 1941. 22pp.: Resolutions adopted by the convention in support of UMWA in captive mines dispute@ UMWA delegation to convention@ plans for convention in support of the Townsend plan@ call for the convention; James B. Carey@ Percy Tetlow@ P, 1 (Reel 7)
  - CIO--Audits. 1941. 18pp.: Financial matters@ CIO support of affiliates@ UMWA loans to CIO@ payment of per capita@ The CIO News@ CIO committee on Latin American affairs. John O'Leary@ John Ghizzoni@ David J. McDonald@ Kathryn Lewis., 2 (Reel 7)
  - CIO--Economic Division., 1941; 3 (Reel 7)
    49 pp.: Use of cost of living and wage indexes in wage agreements; change in name of unemployment division to economic division; economic analysis of industrial statistics; economic effects of national defense mobilization; James B. Carey; Ralph Hetzel; Philip Murray.
  - CIO--Housing Committee., 1941; 4 (Reel 7)
    2 pp.: Legislative programs; Federal Works Agency; Thomas Kennedy.
  - CIO--Legislative Committee and Legal Department., 1941; 5 (Reel 7)
    84 pp.: Difficulties with Colorado coal production; legislative programs; national defense property requisition authorization; anti-labor legislation; pardon efforts in California King-Ramsey-Connor case; NLRB elections; petition for writ of certiorari before the US Supreme Court on southern poll tax case; Southern Conference for Human Welfare; Labor's Non-Partisan League; FBI budget appropriations; use of injunctions and picketing in labor disputes; Lee Pressman; Thomas Kennedy; Josephine Roche; Philip Murray.
  - CIO--Maritime Committee., 1941; 6 (Reel 7)
    5 pp.: Support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; Bjorne Halling.
  - CIO--Social Security Committee., 1941; 7 (Reel 7)
    126 pp.: Proposed amendments to state unemployment compensation laws; Federal Security Agency Social Security Board; Interstate Conference on Employment Security Agencies; John Brophy.
  - CIO--Women's Auxiliary., 1941; 8 (Reel 7)
    39 pp.: National Coordinating Committee for Women's Auxiliaries; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; plans for conference; Oil Workers International Union ladies auxiliary; 1941 CIO convention resolutions regarding women's auxiliaries and youth; National Defense Council; public relations efforts of the meat packing industry; Julia Katz; Kathryn Lewis; John Owens.
  - CIO--Office General., 1942; 9 (Reel 7)
    47 pp.: Call 1942 CIO convention; digest of 1942 CIO convention proceedings; war mobilization; War Production Board; National War Labor Board; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; UMWA relations with CIO; 1942 UMWA convention; legislative program;s CIO regional directors and organizers; Philip Murray; James B. Carey; John O'Leary; Thomas Kennedy; Richard Francis; William Dalrymple; W.A. "Tony" Boyle; Frank Hefferly; Henry Allai; David Fowler.
  - CIO--Releases., 1942; 10 (Reel 7)
    429 pp.: National War Labor Board regional directors and advisory boards; war mobilization efforts; political activities; government-labor cooperation; Office of Civilian Defense; legislative programs; CIO-UMWA relations; criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; CIO housing committee; Office of Price Administration; UMWA loans to CIO; Congress of Women's Auxiliaries of the CIO; public relations efforts and radio programs; legal memorandum prepared for the State, County, and Municipal Workers of America in support of the power of municipalities to enter into collective agreements; no-strike pledge; economic analysis of industrial production; anti-poll tax legislation and civil rights programs; AFL-CIO cooperation; Dies Committee; support for Farm Security Administration; unemployment programs; beating of CIO organizer in Port Arthur, Texas; Philip Murray; Len De Caux; Lee Pressman; Nathan E. Cowan; James B. Carey; John Brophy; R.J. Thomas; Reid Robinson; Joseph Curran; Sherman H. Dalrymple; Emil Rieve; Thomas Kennedy; Faye Stephenson; Abram Flaxer; August Scholle; Ralph Hetzel; Allan S. Haywood; Franklin D. Roosevelt.
  - CIO--Publicity Pamphlet., 1942; 11 (Reel 7)
    114 pp.: Federal tax legislation; war mobilization; CIO-UMWA relations; jurisdictional disputes involving UMWA District 50; criticism of UMWA president John L. Lewis; women's auxiliaries; union organization; organization of black workers; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; government-labor cooperation; Len De Caux; Philip Murray; Thomas Kennedy; James B. Carey.
  - CIO--Economic Division., 1942; 12 (Reel 7)
    41 pp.: Economic analysis of industrial production; War Production Board; rationing programs; Ralph Hetzel.
  - CIO--Housing Committee., 1942; 13 (Reel 7)
    8 pp.: Legislative programs; Labor's Non-Partisan League; US Housing Authority appropriations; R.J. Thomas.
  - CIO--Social Security Committee., 1942; 14 (Reel 7)
    13 pp.: Social Security committee report; Federal Security Administration Social Security Board; federal tax proposals; Van A. Bittner.
  - CIO--Women's Auxiliary., 1942; 15 (Reel 7)
    37 pp.: Founding of CIO women's auxiliary committee; proceedings of 1941 conference of the Congress of Women's Auxiliaries of the CIO; national defense mobilization; Philip Murray; Faye Stephenson; Julia Katz; R.J. Thomas
- Minutes, Correspondence, and General Files, 1943-1953 (Reel 8)
  - CIO--General., 1943; 1 (Reel 8)
    89 pp.: Support for UMWA wage negotiations; CIO Committee on Political Action; digest of 1943 CIO convention; public relations efforts; CIO-UMWA relations; support and criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; War Production Board; National War Labor Board; support and criticism of UMWA strike; J. Raymond Walsh; Philip Murray; Ray Torr.
  - CIO--General., 1944; 2 (Reel 8)
    7 pp.: Report on Communist activities at 1944 CIO convention; CIO factionalism and internal politics.
  - CIO--General., 1947; 3 (Reel 8)
    30 pp.: Newsclippings; CIO factionalism and internal politics; Communist influence in CIO; 1947 CIO convention; Marshall Plan; Taft-Hartley Act.
  - CIO--General., 1948; 4 (Reel 8)
    145 pp.: Legislative conference proposal; 1948 CIO convention report by the president; digest of proceedings; factionalism and internal politics; anti-Communist activities; Marshall Plan; Taft-Hartley Act; civil rights programs; resolutions; political activities; 1948 US presidential campaigns; CIO negotiations with UOPWA CIO office unit regarding pension plans; Cecil Owen; Philip Murray; William O. Douglas; Walter White; Harry S Truman; Herbert Hoover; James B. Carey.
  - CIO--General., 1949; 5 (Reel 8)
    63 pp.: Local support for UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis and coal and steel strikes; 1949 CIO convention; anti-Communist activities in CIO; report by the president to the 1949 CIO convention; Taft-Hartley Act; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm); criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; political activities; Philip Murray; John T. Jones.
  - CIO--General., 1950; 6 (Reel 8)
    29 pp.: Economic demands of the IUE in response to the offer of the General Electric Company; economic analysis of General Electric Company; UMWA cooperation with American Newspaper Guild; labor unity proposals@United Steelworkers of America support for UMWA strike; UMWA offer of loan to UAW; local union support for UMWA strike; Thomas Kennedy; Philip Murray; Walter P. Reuther.
  - CIO--Convention., 1950; 7 (Reel 8)
    92 pp.: Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm); 1950 CIO convention; labor unity proposals; call for convention; report by the president to the convention; resolutions committee report; Justin McCarthy; Thomas Kennedy; John T. Jones; John Owens; A.D. Lewis; Philip Murray.
  - CIO--President Murray's Call for Joint United Labor Committee., 1950; 8 (Reel 8)
    123 pp.: Labor unity proposals; newsclippings; press releases; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm); local union and public support for labor unity; Philip Murray; Justin McCarthy; A.J. Hayes; John J. Mates.
  - CIO--General., 1951; 9 (Reel 8)
    5 pp.: CIO contribution to UMWA disaster relief funds; UMWA support for United Steelworkers of America contract negotiations; American Newspaper Guild cooperation with UMWA; Thomas Kennedy; Sam B. Eubanks.
  - CIO--General., 1951; 10 (Reel 8)
    100 pp.: Report by the president to the 1951 CIO convention; union organization; legislative programs; NLRB and court decisions; political activities; maritime committee; housing committee; Social Security committee; Philip Murray.
  - CIO--General., 1952; 11 (Reel 8)
    133 pp.: ACWA cooperation with UMWA; IWA@United Steelworkers of America dissatisfaction with CIO policies; death of Philip Murray; report scheduled to be delivered by the president to the 1952 CIO convention; union organization; legislative programs; NLRB and court decisions; political activities; committee to abolish discrimination; Social Security committee; maritime committee; housing committee; Wage Stabilization Board appointments; Taft-Hartley Act; southern organizing campaign; use of injunctions in labor disputes; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm)@United Steelworkers of America contract negotiations; HUAC; testimony of John Brophy regarding allegations of his cooperation with Communists; Jacob F. Potofsky; Thomas Kennedy; Philip Murray; Harry S Truman; Cecil Owen; Justin McCarthy; John Brophy
  - CIO--General., 1953; 12 (Reel 8)
    95 pp.: United Steelworkers of America relations with CIO; UMWA contribution to the American Newspaper Guild; Moral Rearmament Movement (MRA); Crusade for Freedom Conference; labor unity negotiations; Textile Union Workers of America competition with United Textile Workers-AFL; Communications Workers of America constitution; Taft-Hartley Act; the Sidney Hillman Foundation; death of Allan S. Haywood; National Citizens Commission for the Public Schools; John Owens; Thomas Kennedy; Joseph F. Collis; Walter P. Reuther; Emil Rieve; Mrs. Allan S. Haywood.
  - CIO--Convention and General., 1953; 13 (Reel 8)
    258 pp.: Resolutions committee report; report by the president; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; union organization; southern organizing campaign; legislative programs; Taft-Hartley Act; NLRB and court decisions; international labor relations; political activities; civil rights activities; Social Security committee; maritime committee; housing committee; Crusade for Freedom Conference; reorganization of CIO; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm); Walter P. Reuther; Cecil Owen; Justin McCarthy.
- Minutes, Correspondence, and General Files, 1922-1942; Alabama through Arkansas, 1937-1942 (Reel 9)
  - CIO--Convention and General., 1954; 1 (Reel 9)
    109 pp.: Digest of 1954 CIO convention proceedings; report by the president; union organization; resolutions of the convention; legislative programs; call to the convention; US Department of Labor; right-to-work legislation proposals; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; ICFTU; Taft-Hartley Act amendments@United Steelworkers of America relations with CIO; US foreign policy; Jewish-American labor representatives and US relations with Arab states; Walter P. Reuther; Dwight D. Eisenhower; James P. Mitchell; J.H. Oldenbroek; Arthur J. Goldberg; Robert Oliver; John Foster Dulles; Matthew Woll.
  - CIO--General., 1955; 2 (Reel 9)
    41 pp.: UMWA request for repayment of loans to CIO; National Union of Mineworkers; ICFTU; international labor relations; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; jurisdictional dispute between United Brewery, Flour, Cereal, Soft Drink, and Distillery Workers and IBT; James B. Carey; John Owens; John Brophy; Thomas Kennedy; Victor G. Reuther; Karl F. Feller; Walter P. Reuther.
  - CIO--General., 3 (Reel 9)
    21pp: CIO convention to ratify AFL-CIO merger; unemployment insurance plans; UAW contract negotiations with Ford Motor Company; Americans for Democratic Action convention; international labor relations; Arthur J. Goldberg; Victor G. Reuther; Justin McCarthy.
  - UMWA Loans and Contributions to CIO and Miscellaneous., 1935-1955; 4 (Reel 9)